RG 004:125, Sharon Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Sharon Probate Court records
1755-1939
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Sharon District)
44 cubic feet
Record books, 1757-1928; Probate files, 1755-1939.
RG004_125
1949-005 and 2011-040
Historical Note
Sharon, Litchfield County, Town established in October 1739
The Sharon Probate District was constituted June 6, 1846, from the Sharon Probate District. The Sharon Probate District merged with the Canaan, Cornwall, Norfolk, and Salisbury Probate Districts on January 1, 2007 to create the Northwest Corner Probate District. The Northwest Corner Probate District merged with the Harwinton, Litchfield, and Thomaston Probate Districts on January 5, 2011, to create the Litchfield Hills Probate District. The Litchfield Hills Probate District serves the municipalities of Canaan, Cornwall, Harwinton, Kent, Litchfield, Morris, Norfolk, North Canaan, Salisbury, Sharon, Thomaston, and Warren.
Town of Sharon, Probate District chronology:
October 1739 - October 1742, New Haven District
October 1742 - October 1755, Litchfield District
October 1755 - December 31, 2006, Sharon District
January 1, 2007 - January 4, 2011, Northwest Corner District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Litchfield Hills District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volume 2-42, 1757-1928. Volume 1 was not transferred to the Connecticut State Library. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 42. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1755-1939. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2011-040 are numnbered 2 to 42. Volumes 2 to 25 are also designated by a letter B to Z, for example "B or 2", " C or 3", etc. Volume 26 is a General Index. There is a volume of wills numbered 1 and a volume of bonds that is unnumbered.
Probate files in accession 1949-005 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1949-005 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Sharon
Places:
Sharon (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-040, Record books, 1757-1928, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED pending review by State Archives staff as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 2-24, 27-30, 32-33, 35, 37-39, 1847-1922; probate files 1755-1880 (Accession 1949-005); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the. Volumes 25-26, 31, 34, and 36 were not filmed.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1949-005 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 22, 1949.
The record books in accession 2011-040 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 28, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1757-1928; 21 cubic feet (34 volumes); 2011-040
  Volume A or 1 was not transferred to the Connecticut State Library
  - Records, 1757-1762 (Volume B or 2)
  - Records, 1757-1771 (Volume C or 3)
  - Records, 1771-1776 (Volume D or 4)
  - Records, 1777-1783 (Volume E or 5)
  - Records, 1783-1787 (Volume F or 6)
  - Records, 1787-1792 (Volume G or 7)
  - Records, 1792-1799 (Volume H or 8)
  - Records, 1799-1805 (Volume I or 9)
  - Records, 1811-1813 (Volume L or 11)
  - Records, 1813-1816 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1816-1820 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1820-1824 (Volume O or 14)
  - Records, 1824-1826 (Volume P or 15)
  - Records, 1826-1832 (Volume Q or 16)
  - Records, 1832-1835 (Volume R or 17)
  - Records, 1835-1838 (Volume S or 18)
  - Records, 1838-1840 (Volume T or 19)
  - Records, 1840-1843 (Volume U or 20)
  - Records, 1843-1847 (Volume V or 21)
  - Records, 1847-1855 (Volume W or 22)
  - Records, 1855-1866 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1866-1874 (Volume Y)
  - Records, 1874-1878 (Volume Z or 25)
    Contains orders and decrees, 1874-1878 in beginning of book
  - Records, 1878-1881 (Volume 26)
    Contains orders and decrees, 1878-1884 in beginning of book
  - Records, 1881-1887 (Volume 27)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Orders and decrees, 1884-1895 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1887-1891 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1891-1895 (Volume 30)
  - Orders and decrees, 1895-1908 (Volume 31)
  - Records, 1895-1899 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1899-1903, 1907 (Volume 33)
  - Bonds, 1899-1928 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1903-1909 (Volume 35)
  - Orders and decrees, 1908-1917 (Volume 36)
  - Records, 1908-1912 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1912-1915 (Volume 38)
  - Records, 1915-1922 (Volume 39)
  - Orders and decrees, 1917-1924 (Volume 40)
  - Records, 1919-1921 (Volume 41)
  - Records, 1921-1923 (Volume 42)
  - Record of wills, 1857-1872 (Volume 1)
  - General index from vol 26 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Bonds, 1880-1899 (Volume unnumbered)
- Probate files, 1755-1939; 23 cubic feet; 1949-005
  - Abell - Berry, L. (Drawer 1)
  - Berry, M. - Carter (Drawer 2)
  - Cartwright - Collignan (Drawer 3)
  - Collins - Doyle (Drawer 4)
  - Drake - Fry (Drawer 5)
  - Fulford - Griswold, F. (Drawer 6)
  - Griswold, G. - Hollister, N. (Drawer 7)
  - Hollister, M. - Hotchkiss, F. (Drawer 8)
  - Hotchkiss, G. - Hubbell, J. (Drawer 9)
  - Hubbell, K. - Hutchings (Drawer 10)
  - Hutchinson - Jackson, P. (Drawer 11)
  - Jackson, Q. -Johnson, J. (Drawer 12)
  - Johnson, K. - Keeler (Drawer 13)
  - Kehoe - King (Drawer 14)
  - Kingsbury - Knibloe (Drawer 15)
  - Knibloes - Lambert, G. (Drawer 16)
  - Lambert, H. - Lango (Drawer 17)
  - Larkin - Levi (Drawer 18)
  - Lewis - Loper (Drawer 19)
  - Lord - Loveridge (Drawer 20)
  - Low - MacDonald (Drawer 21)
  - MacKelvey - Mallaby (Drawer 22)
  - Mallory - Mason (Drawer 23)
  - Masters - Mitchell (Drawer 24)
  - Monroe - Moulton (Drawer 25)
  - Mow - Northrup (Drawer 26)
  - Norton - Pardee, I. (Drawer 27)
  - Pardee, J. - Pease (Drawer 28)
  - Peck, A. - Peck, Z. (Drawer 29)
  - Peet - Perlee (Drawer 30)
  - Perry - Pierce (Drawer 31)
  - Pierson - Pratt (Drawer 32)
  - Prediger - Prindle, R. (Drawer 33)
  - Prindle, S. - Reed, B. (Drawer 34)
  - Reed, C. - Reed, M. (Drawer 35)
  - Reed, N. - Rinehardt (Drawer 36)
  - Ripley - Root, I. (Drawer 37)
  - Root, J. - Ryerson (Drawer 38)
  - Sabin - Sanford, C. (Drawer 39)
  - Sanford, D. - Sedgwick, C. (Drawer 40)
  - Sedgwick, D. - Skiff, H. (Drawer 41)
  - Skiff, I. - Smith, F. (Drawer 42)
  - Smith, G. - Smith, R. (Drawer 43)
  - Smith, S. - Stahovec (Drawer 44)
  - Stanton - Stoddard, H. (Drawer 45)
  - Stoddard, I. - Sutton (Drawer 46)
  - Swain - Taylor, D. (Drawer 47)
  - Taylor, E. - Ticknor, L. (Drawer 48)
  - Ticknor, M. - Treadway, B. (Drawer 49)
  - Treadway - Waitt, Anna (Drawer 50)
  - Waitt, Arthur - Wells (Drawer 51)
  - Welton - Wike, F. (Drawer 52)
  - Wike, G. - Winchester (Drawer 53)
  - Winegar - Woodward, I. (Drawer 54)
  - Woodward, J. - Zinn (Drawer 55)
- Inventory Control Book, 1755-1939; T003073
  Index of probate files in accession 1949-005
  Also known as the Godard Digest